ARNOLD HWANG

A: Seattle Metro Area | E: arnold449007@gmail.com | LI: linkedin.com/in/arnold-hwang-a7536098 | GIT: github.com/arhwang12

SUMMARY

Data engineer with years of experience in variety of industries. Able to discover unique data insights and apply statistical testing, feature engineering methods and machine learning algorithms. Strong technology and research professional focused on solving various problems with entrepreneurial spirit through data-driven decisions.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Project Management • Programming: SQL, Python, PySpark, R • Various BI Tools • Data Visualization and Analysis • Data Mining • Azure • Machine Learning • Predictive Modeling

EXPERIENCE

INTUIT | Mountainview, CA

Data Engineer/Scientist

February 2022 – August 2022

- Engineered model that helps small businesses maintain their customer base by providing them loan options
- Worked with balance sheets and transaction statements to gain understanding of spending patterns and whether businesses can pay off their loans

UNIFY CONSULTING | Kirkland, WA

Data Engineer/Analyst

April 2021 - March 2022

- Created data flow process that starting from server database and ends within visualization platform that provides clients KPIs, graphs/charts and other relevant vendor management info within entire supply chain process
- Performed data validation techniques using SQL, Python and other software tools to ensure all data is being flowed correctly

MICROSOFT | Redmond, WA

Data Scientist

COLLABERA, INC

January 2020 – October 2021

- Created highly accurate time series model that predicts department's spending patterns to understand budget projections
- Managed and produced reports/dashboards that helps employees and executives gain valuable insight
 METIA

 July 2019 September 2019
- Improved content, analytical system with high accuracy that gives clients a better understanding of their customers/users
- Developed and validated NLP product through machine learning algorithms using Python and R that applies text mining and other data processing techniques

FACEBOOK VIA FILTER DIGITAL | Redmond, WA

Data Scientist

September 2017 – January

2019

- Designed data pipeline in cleansing and wrangling raw data for analyzing results
- Successfully extracted data using SQL, designed efficient Python algorithms to cleanse and manipulate

experimental data and created Tableau reports/dashboards

• Developed better understanding of user, virtual reality behavior through feature engineering techniques, A/B testing, and machine learning models

AMAZON VIA ROBERT HALF | Seattle, WA

Data Analyst April 2016 – December 2016

Lead the team in resolving diverse customer issues during peak seasons and unexpected periods of backlog

- Resolved cases by working with Amazon fulfillment centers that includes solving mislabeled inventory and handling damaged items to improve customer and seller experience
- Established effective relationships with sellers by answering relevant questions regarding their inventory
- Manipulated seller, inventory data through Excel and developed better understanding of supply chain operations

EDUCATION

MICROSOFT - PROFESSIONAL PROGRAM | Redmond, WA 2018 - 2019

Certificate, Data Science

Dual Degree

Whitworth University 2009 - 2014 Bachelor's Degree - Applied Physics

Columbia University 2012 -2014

Bachelor's Degree - Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering